Finding Aid for James J. Blanchard Papers, 1982-2002
Bentley Historical Library
- Visual Materials
  - Photographs
    - Gubernatorial and post-gubernatorial photographs and albums (Box 309)
    - Gubernatorial, political, and career as US Ambassador to Canada (Box 341)
    - Gubernatorial, political, and career as US Ambassador to Canada (Box 342)
    - Gubernatorial, political, and career as US Ambassador to Canada (Box 343)
    - Gubernatorial, political, and career as US Ambassador to Canada (Box 344)
    - Oversize photos and memorabilia (Box 345)
- Sound recordings
  The series contains 102 audio cassette tapes, three reel-to-reel tapes, and three micro-cassette tapes. Dated from the 1980s, the content of these tapes is varied and includes recordings of the 1986 Democratic Convention, news conferences, speeches and recordings of Republican meetings, news conferences, and conventions. A large portion of the content is unlabeled and unidentified.
  - Sound recordings (Box 310)
    (contents not listed)
  - Sound recordings (Box 345)
Related Material
The researcher is advised that the Bentley Historical Library has other holdings directly related to the James J. Blanchard collection. The most immediately connected is the Janet Fox Blanchard collection, which documents her status and efforts as James Blanchard's first lady from 1989 to 1990. Other natural research links exist between the Blanchard collection and the collections of his gubernatorial forebears (William Milliken, George Romney, John Swainson, G. Mennen Williams, et al.) and the Bentley's holdings on the Democratic Party of Michigan.